Guide to the Papers of Harrison Salisbury,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Harrison Salisbury Papers,
1927-1999
Salisbury, Harrison E. (Harrison Evans), 1908-1993.
290 linear ft. (ca. 200,000) items in 677 boxes, 1 mapcase drawer, and 4 flat boxes
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY. 10027
5685745
Biographical Note
The American journalist Harrison E. Salisbury (1908-1993) was well-known for his reporting and books on the Soviet Union. A distinguished correspondent and editor for the New York Times, he was the first American reporter to visit Hanoi during the Vietnam War. After editing the campus daily at the University of Minnesota and working as a reporter for the Minneapolis Journal, he decided to pursue a career in journalism. Salisbury took a job with the United Press in St. Paul, soon circulating through other UP bureaus in Chicago, Washington D.C., and New York before being sent to Europe in 1942, where he visited London and Moscow on assignment. In 1944, Salisbury covered the Russian army's victory over the retreating German troops, which he later used as the basis for a series of articles for Colliers magazine and as a book entitled Russia on the Way 1946.
He joined the New York Times and returned to the Soviet Union in 1949 as the Times Russian correspondent. His reports from Moscow were heavily censored and were seen as controversial in the McCarthy anti-Communist atmosphere. After travelling through Siberia in the spring of 1954, he wrote a 14-part report "Russia Re-viewed," which received the 1955 Pulitzer Prize for international reporting. Although barred from the Soviet Union for five years after receiving the Pulitzer Prize, Salisbury was able to tour Poland Bulgaria Rumania and Albania in 1957 and his report on the deterioration of Communism in Eastern Europe led to a George Polk Memorial award for foreign news coverage. Allowed to visit the Soviet Union in 1959 and 1961-1962 Salisbury wrote several books describing the changes in the post-Stalin era. He also published Moscow Journal The End of Stalin 1961 which included the censored dispatches from his earlier five-year residence in Moscow. His knowledge of Stalin's regime provided the background for his well-received first novel The Northern Palmyra Affair (1962).
In 1962 Salisbury was named national news editor of the Times. He supervised the paper's excellent coverage of President Kennedy's assassination and in 1964 became assistant managing editor. In 1972 he was elevated to the rank of associate editor. At the end of 1973 he retired from the New York Times. After leaving The Times Salisbury continued to write and publish. He wrote about the Soviet Union in a series of books including Black Night White Snow (1978), One Hundred Years of Revolution (1983), and A Journey for Our Times A Memoir (1983, which also narrates his boyhood and early career as a journalist. His memoirs were elaborated in another book published in 1988 entitled A Time of Change. In retirement Salisbury traveled several times to China and wrote a book describing his history of the making of the Chinese Red Army following the course of the Long March: The Long March: The Untold Story (1985). Salisbury's reports on North Vietnam were given the Overseas Press Club and George Polk Memorial Awards and his experience was described in the book Behind the Lines (1967); he also wrote Orbit of China (1967), the best-seller The 900 Days: The Siege of Leningrad (1969) and War Between Russia and China (1969). Salisbury's coverage of Al Capone's trial to his presence at the 1989 Tianamen Square uprising were described in Tianamen Diary Thirteen Days in June (1988).
Salisbury's other works inlcude The Kingdom and the Power (1966), Russia in Revolution (1979), The New Emperors: China in the Era of Mao and Deng (1992), and Heroes of My Time (1993). Salisbury wrote an authorized but independent history of the New York Times which was published as Without Fear or Favor (1980), which discusses the shift in the paper from news reporting to an active engagement in political events. Salisbury focuses his story on the decision of the Times to print the secret study of the Vietnam War, the Pentagon Papers which provoked a confrontation with the Nixon administration. In 1964 he married Charlotte Young Rand and they lived in Manhattan and Taconic, Connecticut.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, documents, photographs, notes, inteviews, articles, newspapers, clippings, and press releases of Harrison Evans Salisbury, a prominent journalist and editor.
Arrangement
Arranged in three series
Series I. Cataloged Correspondence
Series II. Arranged Correspondnece
SeriesIII. Box Listing (unsorted)
Subjects
New York Times Company.; Oakes, John B. (John Bertram), 1913-2001.; Newspaper publishing.; Journalists.; Newspapers--Sections, columns, etc.; Newspaper editors.
Access Restrictions
Available for faculty, students, and researchers engaged in scholarly publication projects.
664 boxes of arranged material are located off-site and require advance notice of intent to use.
Acquisition
Estate of Harrison Salisbury Gift 1993
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondece
  - Benton, William To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 1955-1972, (32 t.l.s., 1 a.l.s.) (Box 1)
    [Some also to Charlotte Salisbury]
  - Bhutto, Zulfikar Ali To Harrison E. Salisbury, Karachi, 26 Aug 1969, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 1)
    [With related letter]
  - Black, Cyril Edwin To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York and Princeton, 1962-1979, (5 t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Bly, Robert To Harrison E. Salisbury, v.p.1971-1987, (6 a.l.s., 1 a.p.c.s., 1 Telegram, 1 a.n.s.) (Box 1)
  - Bond, Julian To The New York Times, Atlanta Ga.1963 and 1968, (2 t.l.s. (both with clippings)) (Box 1)
  - Boorstin, Daniel J. To Harrison E. Salisbury, Washington, 6 Sept 1985, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Bowles, Chester To Arthur Hays Sulzberger, New Delhi, 7 Mar 1953, (12 p. t.l.s.) (Box 1)
    [With carbon copy of letter from Sulzberger]
  - Bowles, Chester To Harrison E. Salisbury, Washington and New Delhi, 1959-1968, (12 t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Bowles, Chester To Harrison and Charlotte Salisbury, n.p.n.d., ( a.p.c.s.) (Box 1)
  - Breslin, Jimmy To Abraham M. Rosenthal or Arthur Gelb, New York, 24 Aug 1973, (1 p. Telegram) (Box 2)
    [With related letter on same sheet]
  - Brooks, Gladys Rice Billings (Mrs. Van Wyck) To Charlotte Young Salisbury (Mrs. Harrison E.), New York and Bridgewater Conn.1969 and 1971, (2 a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Brooks, Gladys Rice Billings (Mrs. Van Wyck) To Harrison E. Salisbury, Bridgewater, 1971 and 1975, (2 a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Brooks, Gwendolyn To Harrison E. Salisbury, v.p.1982-1987, (5 a.l.s., 1 Printed Announcements) (Box 2)
  - Brooks, Gwendolyn To Charlotte Young Salisbury, Chicago, 24 Jul 1993, (4 p. a.l.s.) (Box 2)
    [With envelope]
  - Brown, Helen Gurley (Mrs. David) To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 1983-1989, (3 t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Brown, Helen Gurley (Mrs. David) To Charlotte Young Salisbury (Mrs. Harrison E.), New York, 8 Jul 1993, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Brustein, Robert To Harrison E. Salisbury, Vineyard Haven Mass.1965, (3 t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Brzezinski, Zbigniew To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 1963-1968, (4 t.l.s., 1 t.l.) (Box 2)
    [Carbon copy with a.n.s. to Arthur Ochs Sulzberger]
  - Buchanan, Patrick J. To Harrison E. Salisbury, Washington, 1974-1975, (2 t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Buckley, William Frank, Jr. To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York and n.p.1963-1986, (12 t.l.s., 1 t.l. with a.n.s.) (Box 2)
  - Bundy, William P. To Harrison E. Salisbury, v.p.1967-1975, (6 t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Burger, Warren Earl To Harrison E. Salisbury, Washington, Jul 1980, (2 t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Caen, Herb To Harrison E. Salisbury, San Francisco, 13 Oct 1987, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Calder, Alexander and Louisa To Harrison E. Salisbury, Sache France, 1967, (2 a.p.c.s.) (Box 2)
  - Caldwell, Erskine To Harrison E. Salisbury, Scottsdale Ariz.1984 and 1986, (2 t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Canfield, Cass To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 1954-1983, (81 t.l.s., 1 t.l., 4 a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Canfield, Cass To Evan Thomas, New York, 23 Jan 1967, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Carroll, Wallace To Harrison E. Salisbury, v.p.1957-1974, (5 t.l.s., 1 t.l. (mimeograph), 1 p.l. with a.n.s.) (Box 2)
  - Carroll, Wallace To O'Neill, Washington, 15 Aug 1962, (1 p. t.l.) (Box 2)
    [Mimeograph, with t.l. from Salisbury on same sheet]
  - Catledge, Turner To Julius Ochs Adler, New York, 2 Oct 1950, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
    [With Telegram to Salisbury]
  - Catledge, Turner To Joseph Callahan, New York, 19 Mar 1966, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Catledge, Turner To E. Clifton Daniel, New York, 1964-1966, (3 t.l.) (Box 2)
  - Catledge, Turner To Harrison E. Salisbury, v.p.1949-1968, (22 t.l.s., 3 telegrams, 17 t.l., 1 a.p.c.s.) (Box 2)
  - Catledge, Turner To Arthur Ochs Sulzberger, New York, 25 Aug 1964, (1 p. t.l.) (Box 2)
    [With a.n.s. from Sulzberger on same page]
  - Cerf, Bennett A. To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 4 Mar 1969, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 3)
  - Chancellor, John To Harrison E. Salisbury, Washington and New York, 1965 and 1980, (2 t.l.s.) (Box 3)
  - Chomsky, Noam To Harrison E. Salisbury, Cambridge Mass.13 Jan 1969, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 3)
  - Clark, Joe To Harrison E. Salisbury, v.p.1954-1988, (12 t.l.s., 1 Telegram, 1 a.p.c.s., 1 a.l.s.) (Box 3)
  - Clark, Joe To Mario M. Cuomo, New York, 15 Mar 1988, (3 p. t.l.s.) (Box 3)
    [Photo copy; with letter to Salisbury, 21 March 1988]
  - Clifford, Clark M. To Harrison E. Salisbury, Washington, 1973 and 1975, (2 t.l.s.) (Box 3)
  - Clinchy, Everett R. To Julius Ochs Adler, New York, 22 Sept 1954, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 3)
  - Clinchy, Everett R. To Harrison E. Salisbury, v.p.1954-1982, (37 t.l.s., 1 t.l., 12 a.l.s., 1 a.n.s.) (Box 3)
  - Clinchy, Everett R. To Charlotte Young Salisbury (Mrs. Harrison E.), New York, 12 May 1980, (2p. a.l.s.) (Box 3)
  - Commager, Henry Steele To Harrison E. Salisbury, Amherst Mass. and Cambridge U.K.1962-1985, (10 t.l.s.) (Box 3)
  - Conquest, Robert To Harrison E. Salisbury, London, 1969-1973, (4 t.l.s.) (Box 3)
  - Cousins, Norman To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York and Los Angeles, 1959-1990, (16 t.l.s.) (Box 3)
  - Cowley, Malcolm To Harrison E. Salisbury, Sherman Conn.1974-1983, (3 t.l.s., 1 a.l.s., 1 a.p.c.s.) (Box 3)
  - Cowley, Malcolm To William Jay Smith, Sherman Conn.31 Aug 1976, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 3)
    [See letter to Salisbury, same date. With related letter from Smith]
  - Cronkite, Walter To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York and n.p.1970-1978, (4 t.l.s.) (Box 3)
  - Deutsch, Babette To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 1972-1976, (7 t.l.s., 1 t.p.c.s.) (Box 3)
  - Deutsch, Babette To Richard Wilbur, New York, 15 Jun 1975, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 3)
    [Carbon copy]
  - Dickey, James To Harrison E. Salisbury, Columbia S.C.25 Aug 1983, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 3)
  - Djilas, Milovan To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 17 Oct 1968, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 3)
    [With carbon reply]
  - Douglas, William Orville To Harrison E. Salisbury, Washington, 1956 and 1969, (4 t.l.s.) (Box 3)
  - Dulles, Allen W. To Harrison E. Salisbury, Washington, 15 Dec 1956, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 3)
  - Eaton, Cyrus S. To Harrison E. Salisbury, v.p.1956-1974, (71 t.l.s., 1 a.l.s., 5 Telegrams) (Box 3)
  - Edelstein, Julius C. C. To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 1959-1989, (5 t.l.s.) (Box 4)
  - Ehrenberg, Ilya To Harrison E. Salisbury, Moscow, 1961-1965, (6 t.l.s.) (Box 4)
  - Ellsberg, Daniel To Harrison E. Salisbury, n.p.14 Feb 1970, (2 p. a.l.s.) (Box 4)
  - Engle, Paul To Harrison E. Salisbury, Iowa City, 1983-1985, (7 t.l.s.) (Box 4)
  - Ernst, Morris Leopold To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 1968-1974, (28 t.l.s., 2 a.n.s.) (Box 4)
  - Ernst, Morris Leopold To Henry Raymont, New York, 5 Feb 1971, (1 p. t.l.) (Box 4)
    [Carbon copy; a.n.s. to Salisbury on same sheet]
  - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence To Harrison E. Salisbury, San Francisco, 30 Sept 1962, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 4)
  - Fish, Hamilton, Jr. To Harrison E. Salisbury, Washington, 2 Sept 1981, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 4)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield To Mary Pritchard Salisbury (Mrs. Augustus Harrison), Omaha, n.d., (1 p. a.l.s.) (Box 4)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield To Susan May Salisbury, v.p.1916-1943 (most undated), (46 t.l.s., 4 a.l.s., 4 a.p.c.s.) (Box 4)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield n.a., Paris, 19 Nov 1916, (3 p. t.l.) (Box 4)
  - Frankel, Max To James B. Reston, Washington, Feb 1969, (1 p. a.l.s.) (Box 4)
  - Frankel, Max To Harrison E. Salisbury, v.p.1958-1991 (some undated), (31 t.l.s., 8 t.l., 13 a.l.s., 2 a.n.s.) (Box 4)
  - Frankel, Max To Charlotte Young Salisbury (Mrs. Harrison E.), New York, Jul 1993, (1 p. a.l.s.) (Box 4)
  - Frankenthaler, Helen To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York and Bennington Vt.1976-1978, (2 a.l.s., 1 a.p.c.s.) (Box 4)
  - Frankenthaler, Helen To Charlotte Young Salisbury (Mrs Harrison E.), Stamford Conn.14 Jul 1993, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 4)
  - Frankfurter, Felix To Charles Merz, v.p.1937-1960, (16 t.l.s., 12 a.l.s., 1 Telegram) (Box 4)
  - Freeman, Orville L. To Harrison E. Salisbury, St. Paul Minn. and Washington, 1958 and 1965, (2 t.l.s.) (Box 5)
    [One with documents re Boundary Waters Canoe Area]
  - Friendly, Fred W. To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 1968-1978, (4 t.l.s.) (Box 5)
    [Some with related materials]
  - Fulbright, James William To Harrison E. Salisbury, Washington, 1967, (2 t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Fuller, R. Buckminster To Harrison E. Salisbury, v.p. 1968-1982, (1 Telegram, 4 t.l.s., 1 card with a.n.s.) (Box 5)
  - Galbraith, John Kenneth To Harrison E. Salisbury, Cambridge Mass.1980-1983, (3 t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Gallup, George To Harrison E. Salisbury, Princeton N.J.1968, (5 t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Gallup, George To James B. Reston, Princeton N.J.10 Jul 1969, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 5)
    [With letter from Reston to E.C. Daniel]
  - Gill, Brendan To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 31 Jul 1968, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Gingrich, Arnold To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 1967 and 1976, (2 t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Ginsberg, Allen To Harrison E. Salisbury, v.p. 1959-1986, (4 t.l.s., 7 a.l.s., 1 a.n.s., 3 a.p.c.s.) (Box 5)
  - Ginsberg, Allen To Charlotte Young Salisbury (Mrs. Harrison E.), New York, 4 Aug 1993, (1 p. a.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Ginsberg, Allen To Claude Sitton, San Francisco, 8 Jul 1968, (1 p. a.l.s.) (Box 5)
    [With related documents]
  - Gray, Francine du Plessix To Harrison E. Salisbury, v.p. 1980-1991 (several n.d.), (2 t.l.s., 5 a.l.s., 4 a.p.c.s.) (Box 5)
  - Gray, Francine du Plessix To Charlotte Young Salsibury (Mrs. Harrison E.), Warren Conn.7 Jul 1993, (2 p. a.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Guggenheim, Harry F. To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York and Garden City N.Y.1962-1968, (4 t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Halberstam, David To Harrison E. Salisbury, v.p. 1965-1992, (5 t.l.s., 7 a.l.s. ) (Box 5)
  - Halberstam, David To Charlotte Young Salisbury (Mrs. Harrison E.), New York, 4 Aug 1993, (1 p. a.l.s.) (Box 5)
    [With envelope, related manuscript]
  - Haley, Alex To Harrison E. Salisbury, Beverly Hills Ca.27 Aug 1985, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Hamill, Pete To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 29 Sept 1985, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Harcourt, Alfred To Dorothy Canfield Fisher, New York, 28 Aug 1918, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 5)
    [With a.l.s. from Fisher to Susan Salisbury on same sheet) -- filed with Fisher letters]
  - Harriman, W. Averell To Harrison E. Salisbury, Paris and Washington, 1969-1983, (3 t.l.s.) (Box 5)
    [Christmas cards.]
  - Hearst, William Randolph, Jr. To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 26 Oct 1960, (1 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 5)
  - Heller, Joseph To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 22 Oct 1980, (1 p. a.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Hellman, Lillian To Harrison E. Salisbury, v.p. 1967-1978, (4 t.l.s. 1 a.p.c.s.) (Box 5)
  - Hersey, John To Harrison E. Salisbury, v.p. 1978-1987, (5 a.l.s., 1 t.l.s.) (Box 5)
    [With John Brooks]
  - Hindus, Maurice Gerschon To Harrison E. Salisbury, Belgrade, 21 Aug 1961, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Hollings, Ernest F. To Harrison E. Salisbury, Washington, 24 Nov 1970, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Hoover, Herbert Clark To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 1958, (2 t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Humphrey, Hubert Horatio To Harrison E. Salisbury, Washington and St. Paul, 1964-1973, (3 t.l.s) (Box 5)
  - Humphrey, Hubert Horatio To Cyrus Eaton, Washington, 5 Jan 1970, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 5)
    [Photo copy -- see Eaton to Salisbury, 14 Jan. 1970]
  - Jackson, Henry M. To Harrison E. Salisbury, Washington, 1963 and 1975, (5 t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Jameson, Storm To Harrison E. Salisbury, Ilkley and Cambridge U.K.1946-1983, (24 t.l.s. 13 a.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Janeway, Eliot To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York and n.p.1964-1974, (10 t.l.s., 2 t.l.) (Box 5)
  - Janeway, Elizabeth Hall (Mrs. Eliot) To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 1964-1975, (3 t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Javits, Jacob Koppel To Harrison E. Salisbury, Washington and New York, 1967-1983, (3 t.l.s.) (Box 5)
  - Johnson, Earl J. To Harrison E. Salisbury, v.p. 1954-1973, (7 t.l.s., 12 a.l.s., 1 a.n.s., 1 a.p.c.s.) (Box 6)
  - Johnson, Lady Bird Taylor (Mrs. Lyndon Baines) To Harrison E. Salisbury, Stonewall Tx.17 Feb 1973, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Johnson, Lyndon Baines To Charles Merz, n.p. 24 Jul 1957, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 6)
    [Enclosure mentioned is missing]
  - Johnson, Lyndon Baines To Harrison Salisbury, Austin, TX, 6 October 1972, (1 page t.l.s. (with envelope)) (Box 6)
  - Jong, Erica To Harrison and Charlotte Salisbury, n.p. 12 May 1983, (1 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 6)
  - Kanin, Garson To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 1983-1985 and n.d., (3 t.l.s., 1 t.l.) (Box 6)
  - Kapitsa, Sergei Petrovich To Harrison Salisbury, Moscow, 9 November 1988, (1 telegram (telex)) (Box 6)
  - Kazin, Alfred To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 1973 and 1983, (3 t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Kazin, Alfred To Charlotte Young Salisbury (Mrs. Harrison E.), New York, 9 Jul 1993, (1 p. a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Keating, Kenneth B. To Harrison E. Salisbury, Washington and New Delhi, 1961-1970, (5 t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Keaton, Diane To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York and London, 1979-1982, (1 t.l.s., 3 a.p.c.s.) (Box 6)
  - Kennan, George Frost To Harrison E. Salisbury, v.p. 1955-1993, (22 t.l.s., 1 t.l., 7 a.l.s., 1 t.p.c.s., 1 a.p.c.s., 1 Telegram) (Box 6)
  - Kennan, George Frost To Charlotte Young Salsibury (Mrs. Harrison E.), Princeton N.J.13 Sept 1993, (1 p. a.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Kennedy, Edward Moore To Harrison E. Salisbury, Washington, 1979-1982, (3 t.l.s., 1 Mailgram ) (Box 6)
  - Kennedy, John Fitzgerald To Georgianna Evans Salisbury (Mrs. Percy P.), Washington, 30 Sept 1963, (1 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 6)
  - Kennedy, John Fitzgerald To Harrison Salisbury, Washington, 16 December 1960, (1 p. t.l.s. (with envelope; sig. washed away) ) (Box 6)
  - Kirk, Alan Goodrich To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 11 May 1962, (1 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 6)
  - Kirk, Grayson To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 1955 and 1965, (2 t.l.s. 1 Telegram) (Box 6)
  - Kirkland, Lane -- see George Meany Knopf, Alfred A. To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 1961-1975, (4 t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Korda, Michael. V To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 1963-1989, (10 t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Kristol, Irving To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 5 Jan 1970, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Krock, Arthur To Harrison E. Salisbury, Washington, 1955-1972, (9 t.l.s., 1 t.l., 4 a.l.s., 1 Telegram) (Box 6)
  - Krock, Arthur To Arthur Hays Sulzberger, New York, Feb 1936, (1 p. a.n.s.) (Box 6)
    [At top of Telegram to Krock from Bertram D. Hulen]
  - Laird, Melvin R. To Harrison E. Salisbury, Washington, 21 May, 1976, (2 p. t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Landers, Ann (Esther Friedman Lederer) To Harrison E. Salisbury, Chicago, 23 Jul 1973, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Lane, Mark To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 1964 and 1966, (2 t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Lasker, Mary (Mrs. Albert D.) To E. Clifton Daniel, New York, n.d., (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Lasker, Mary (Mrs. Albert D.) To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 1966-1971, (4 t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Lattimore, Owen To Harrison E. Salisbury, v.p. 1961-1974, (8 t.l.s., 5 a.l.s. ) (Box 6)
  - Lehman, Orin To Harrison E. Salisbury, Albany N.Y.4 Aug 1978, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 6)
    [With clipping, related letter]
  - Lerner, Max To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 7 Jan 1971, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 6)
  - Levine, Isaac Don To Harrison E. Salisbury, Carlsbad Ca. and Waldorf Md. 1965-1980, (3 t.l.s., 5 a.l.s. ) (Box 6)
  - Lilienthal, David Eli To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 1962-1973, (13 t.l.s., 5 a.l.s. ) (Box 6)
    [Some with enclosures]
  - Lindsay, John Vliet To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 4 May 1987, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 7)
  - Lindsay, John Vliet To Charlotte Young Salisbury (Mrs. Harrison E.), New York, 7 Jul 1993, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 7)
  - Lippmann, Walter To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York and Washington, 1954-1967, (3 t.l.s.) (Box 7)
  - Litvinov, Maxim To Harrison E. Salisbury, Moscow, 9 Apr 1950, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 7)
  - Long, Russell B. To Harrison E. Salisbury, Washington, 17 May 1971, (2 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 7)
  - Luce, Henry R To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 15 Mar 1955, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 7)
  - Lynes, Russell To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 1970-1993, (3 t.l.s., 1 a.l.s., 1 a.n.s.) (Box 7)
  - Lynes, Russell To Israel Shenker, New York, 5 Apr 1970, (1 p. t.l.) (Box 7)
    [Carbon copy; on same sheet as a.n.s. to Salisbury]
  - McCarthy, Mary To Harrison E. Salisbury, Paris, 10 Apr 1987, (1 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 7)
    [With envelope, 2 related letters]
  - McCormick, Ken To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 1962-1990, (20 t.l.s.) (Box 7)
  - Macdonald, Dwight To Harrison E. Salisbury, v.p. 1973-1982, (6 t.l.s., 2 a.l.s., 1 a.l.) (Box 7)
  - McGill, William J. To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 1970-1977, (4 t.l.s.) (Box 7)
  - McGovern, George Stanley To Harrison E. Salisbury, Washington, 1967-1978, (4 t.l.s., 1 a.n.s.) (Box 7)
    [On text of speech]
  - MacIver, Robert M. To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 1958 and 1961, (3 t.l.s.) (Box 7)
  - MacLeish, Archibald To Turner Catledge, Conway Mass.1962, (1 t.l.s., 1 Telegram) (Box 7)
  - MacLeish, Archibald To Harrison E. Salisbury, Conway Mass. and n.p.1971-1976, (7 a.l.s. ) (Box 7)
  - Macrae, Elliott To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 1956-1967, (6 t.l.s.) (Box 7)
  - McWillliams, Carey To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York, 1962 and 1967, (3 t.l.s.) (Box 7)
  - Mailer, Norman To Harrison E. Salisbury, Brooklyn, 18 Mar 1977, (1 p. t.l. ) (Box 7)
    [Photo copy with autograph greeting; related document]
  - Manchester, William To Harrison E. Salisbury, Middletown Conn.1957-1969, (3 t.l.s.) (Box 7)
  - Mansfield, Michael J. To Harrison E. Salisbury, Washington, 11 Sept 1963, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 7)
    [With clippings; carbon reply]
  - Markel, Lester To Turner Catledge, New York, 15 Mar 1965, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 7)
    [Signed with initials]
  - Markel, Lester To E. Clifton Daniel, New York, 1964-1965, (2 t.l.s.) (Box 7)
  - Markel, Lester To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York and London, 1954-1976, (36 t.l.s., 2 Telegram) (Box 7)
  - Markel, Lester To Mr. Schwarz and Mr. Bergman, New York, 20 Dec 1957, (1 p. t.l. ) (Box 7)
  - Marshall, Herbert To Harrison E. Salisbury, Carbondale Ill.1969-1983 (1 n.d.), (9 t.l.s., 1 a.l.s. ) (Box 7)
  - Matthews, Herbert Lionel To Charles Merz, London, 1949, (1 p. Telegram) (Box 7)
  - Matthews, Herbert Lionel To Arthur Hays Sulzberger, New York, 11 Dec 1953, (1 p. t.l.s. ) (Box 7)
  - Matthews, Herbert Lionel To Arthur Hays Sulzberger, New York, 2 Aug 1960, (2 p. t.l.s.) (Box 7)
    [Copy -- see Sulzberger to Merz, 4 Aug. 1960]
  - Matthews, Herbert Lionel To Harrison E. Salisbury, v.p. 1967-1973, (5 t.l.s., 1 a.l.s. ) (Box 7)
  - Meany, George and Lane Kirkland To Harrison E. Salisbury, New York and Washington, 1975, (2 t.l.s.) (Box 7)